[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0e", "question": "How were composer George Gershwin and lyricist Ira Gershwin related?", "answer": "They were brothers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c8c7877e98cb977789ec", "question": "Where is the Sphinx Observatory located?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feccc20ec223966ae8f88a1", "question": "How long did it take to render each frame (1/24th of a second) of the CGI scenes in the movie \"Avatar\"?", "answer": "47 hours", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f45", "question": "What sheriff's alter ego was the masked \"El Kabong\"?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a677", "question": "Which US state was named after the King of France?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80a", "question": "Poutine consists of gravy and cheese curds on top of what?", "answer": "French fries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d2a92596a59cbdfbd391", "question": "Equity State is the official nickname of which state?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe77075eec85e375820b2f9", "question": "Where is the \"Top of Europe\"?", "answer": "Jungfraujoch, Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c3", "question": "How many teeth does Bugs Bunny have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af256b3b63e5727cf5a483f", "question": "What popular toy, that is still widely used today, was invented by Arthur K. Melin in 1958?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ef", "question": "\"Tizona\", was the sword belonging to what national hero?", "answer": "El Cid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f6", "question": "Who put Humpty Dumpty together again in the traditional nursery rhyme?", "answer": "No one", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc2f837cee580c7f8fd1e60", "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Mount Whitney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bf", "question": "Which actor played the role of Dawson on the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\"?", "answer": "James Van Der Beek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339133", "question": "\"The Faerie Queene\" is an incomplete epic poem by which English poet?", "answer": "Edmund Spenser", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a4", "question": "What fruit is grown extensively on Cape Cod?", "answer": "Cranberries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339185", "question": "What TV show had the tagline: Most gripping sitcom since 1380?", "answer": "The Black Adder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339203", "question": "Who finds E.T.?", "answer": "Elliott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b930", "question": "What is the official score of a forfeited major league baseball game?", "answer": "9-0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d53", "question": "How old was J. K. Rowling when she published the first Harry Potter book?", "answer": "31", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c44", "question": "What popular statue was designed by Fredric-Auguste Bartholdi?", "answer": "Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea32aeff048f679a45aae9", "question": "How often do your taste buds regenerate on average?", "answer": "Every ten days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3cf9e4f032c0db195b491", "question": "In which caste would you most likely find a Hindu priest?", "answer": "Traditionally, priests have come from the Brahmin varna.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c7", "question": "The Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris was originally what?", "answer": "Railway Station", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18d", "question": "What year was astronaut Neil Armstrong born?", "answer": "1930", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0c", "question": "What is the name of the gypsy girl who Quasimodo fell in love with?", "answer": "Esmeralda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6bc92fb6c85e9e634ff5e", "question": "Majorca is the largest of which island group?", "answer": "Balearic Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b40d06d333868d34d6df", "question": "What part of the world did the Vikings come from?", "answer": "Scandinavia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe658adae7e414034b5aef5", "question": "Which battle was fought on August 22, 1485?", "answer": "Battle of Bosworth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b700", "question": "What sport is likely to cause pudendal nerve entrapment?", "answer": "Cycling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017374144491cbd7c5a1787", "question": "During the American Civil War, the steamship USS Monitor was converted into what Confederate iron-clad ship?", "answer": "After it was scuttled, the Confederates raised the USS Monitor and retrofitted it to an iron-clad and named it the CSS Virginia.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338995", "question": "Who was married to Andrew Lloyd Webber when he composed \"The Phantom of the Opera\" for her voice?", "answer": "Sarah Brightman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a265", "question": "Who established Paisley Park as his own record label?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59220535a4edfd43a087ade8", "question": "How high is the center of the tennis court net?", "answer": "3 feet, or 91 centimetres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce1", "question": "What fashion brand was co-founded by Jay-Z and Damon Dash?", "answer": "Rocawear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a654", "question": "The shoreline of which US state is broken by Albemarle Sound?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad77", "question": "Who was the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic ocean?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71e", "question": "With what do you \"Deck the Halls\"?", "answer": "Boughs of Holly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062bb1c9d816e292245c23", "question": "Frida Kahlo was married to which famous muralist?", "answer": "Diego Rivera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b28a", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Bucephalus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339546", "question": "What TV show starred Suzanne Somers as Carol Foster/Lambert?", "answer": "Step by Step", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c658", "question": "Mach refers to the speed of what?", "answer": "Sound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33a", "question": "What actress played 4 roles in the 1975 film \"Trilogy of Terror\"?", "answer": "Karen Black", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab27", "question": "Antananarivo is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f4b7fa5fdd6dd25324e4", "question": "Bengui is the capital of which land-locked country?", "answer": "Central African Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2cfa22596a59cbdfbd371", "question": "Who said, \"Do I not destroy my enemies when I make them my friends\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af24bb8844f4236002b95b0", "question": "The names of how many countries start with the letter \"A\"?", "answer": "12", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd0", "question": "In which much told legend does a magician sell his soul to the devil?", "answer": "Faust", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c34", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b479e662d71a53650feb", "question": "Why did Michelangelo dislike Raphael?", "answer": "He thought Raphael was copying him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6016015dfe83fe1f2a824c5e", "question": "Traditional May Day celebrations in Germany and surrounding nations was tied-in with the recognition of which saint?", "answer": "Saint Walpurgis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf8", "question": "Who was the first Russian woman to win a Wimbledon singles title?", "answer": "Maria Sharapova", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e4", "question": "What was the original working title of the Beatles movie \"Help!\"?", "answer": "Eight Arms To Hold You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d4", "question": "On the ph scale, what number indicates neutrality?", "answer": "7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ec", "question": "Which is the longest river in Australia?", "answer": "Murray River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ec", "question": "What is the astronomical term for three celestial bodies aligning?", "answer": "Syzygy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339299", "question": "What is the main difference between the character Starbuck in the 70's version of \"Battlestar Galact", "answer": "Starbuck is a female in the reboot and a male in the 70's version", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99cd621a8909e5c332d3b", "question": "What is the capita of Corsica?", "answer": "Ajaccio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47c", "question": "In which city is the European Court of Justice?", "answer": "Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c758", "question": "What vitamin, found in carrots, helps maintain the acuity of your vision?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5906835cff9c0647b50a80a6", "question": "Alec Baldwin started hosting which ABC show on June 26, 2016?", "answer": "Match Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02c", "question": "By marrying Prince Rainier, Grace Kelly became princess of what nation?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f3", "question": "What is the nickname of the car Memphis Raines was obsessed with in the movie \"Gone in 60 seconds\"?", "answer": "Eleanor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1da", "question": "What organization in the US was co-founded by Ballington Booth?", "answer": "Volunteers of America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b309", "question": "Who was found in a \"spider hole\" on December 13, 2003?", "answer": "Saddam Hussein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d9462596a59cbdfbd3c2", "question": "For which battle did Washington famously cross the Delaware River?", "answer": "Trenton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd660d6a5bfecdd737e0838", "question": "Who was the most Googled person of 2018?", "answer": "Meghan Markle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f5660b33a95c66dc4fe75d", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6c", "question": "What was the name of the 80\u2019s band formed by Roland Orzabal and Curt Smith?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77d30ab2c8f322317fef", "question": "What country does motor racing's Jacques Villeneuve come from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c54", "question": "Whitney Houston's self-titled debut album was released in what year?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029d5acad1ec93f27df74c", "question": "Where did Thomas Lipton open his first grocery store?", "answer": "Glasgow, Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e94", "question": "What movie did the villain Travis Bickle appear in?", "answer": "Taxi Driver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf2", "question": "Hydrosis is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Sweating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6d", "question": "What explorer was the first to sail around the southern tip of South America, and name it Cape Horn?", "answer": "William Schouten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c756", "question": "In the culinary world, what does MSG short for?", "answer": "Monosodium glutamate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81e", "question": "What song contains the line \"I feel stupid and contagious\"?", "answer": "Smells Like Teen Spirit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0c", "question": "What science-fiction author founded the Church of Scientology in 1953?", "answer": "L. Ron Hubbard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bbd2d96d05b23b28164f", "question": "What event prompted the first New Year\u2019s Eve ball drop in Times Square?", "answer": "New York Times paper owner Adolph Ochs hired a metal worker to build the ball-drop due to a fireworks ban in the city.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973e", "question": "What was Fonzie's fill name on the TV show \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Arthur Herbert Fonzarelli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca25", "question": "How many kilograms make up a short ton?", "answer": "907", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15d", "question": "Which city is served by Schwechat airport?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb5", "question": "What country\u2019s air force was destroyed on the ground on June 5, 1967?", "answer": "Egypt\u2019s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fe", "question": "What compound makes up around 60% of the human body weight?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc101ec223966ae8f8863", "question": "The 2016 Cavaliers defeated which NBA team to win Cleveland\u2019s first title?", "answer": "Golden State Warriors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ecbc08d98002fdd633bf", "question": "Which US state's way of life and culture is described as Cajun?", "answer": "Louisiana's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173fea44491cbd7c5a17b8", "question": "The Battle of Austerlitz took place during which war?", "answer": "Napoleonic Wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b795", "question": "Christmas caroling began as what old English custom?", "answer": "Wassailing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e2", "question": "Which actress turned singer released an album in 2009 entitled \"Come To Life\"?", "answer": "Natalie Imbruglia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded30aea2747c8aff16d44", "question": "Which band took their name from a type of light motor truck manufactured primarily before World War II?", "answer": "REO Speedwagon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fca", "question": "Which Canadian province is the setting for the novel \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a0", "question": "What deep sea exploration device was invented by William Beebe?", "answer": "Bathysphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2d", "question": "What dessert consists of beaten egg whites, sugar, and cream of tartar?", "answer": "Meringue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cbd194b094db9158309b", "question": "What nationality is Denis Villeneuve, director of the 2016 film \"Arrival\"?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937e98708d98002fdd6339a", "question": "The alcoholic beverage \"Poteen\" originates from which country?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f70f0a9e54d890926f6d9", "question": "Who created the design for Mount Rushmore?", "answer": "Sculptor\u00a0Gutzon Borglum\u00a0created the design and oversaw the project's execution from 1927 to 1941 with his son,\u00a0Lincoln's help.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121a1963c99d48cd169b00", "question": "What kind of nut is used to make marzipan?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3f0528b5801b8f54a7fba", "question": "Paris\u2019 Notre Dame Cathedral was built on the ruins of what?", "answer": "A pagan temple to Jupiter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b60ec223966ae8f883c", "question": "Lady Gaga derived her stage name from a song performed by which legendary band?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be10", "question": "Which one of Strawberry Shortcake's four original toy \"friends\" was a boy?", "answer": "Huckleberry Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d20", "question": "What Presidential medal did Helen Keller win?", "answer": "Presidential Medal of Freedom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a023", "question": "What is the name of the female co-anchor who died in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Diane Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5691c73aa70ea0b70b2c", "question": "Which city is traditionally said to be built on seven hills?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db788c0ab2c8f322317ff4", "question": "What is the capital of Panama?", "answer": "Panama City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96e9e23c87fd04dd15e3a", "question": "As of 2020, who was the last human to walk on the moon?", "answer": "Eugene Cernan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a3", "question": "What three-letter word means the smallest piece of information used by a computer?", "answer": "Bit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c986", "question": "The Big Dipper is part of what constellation?", "answer": "Ursa Major", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339917", "question": "What daytime soap opera takes place in the fictional town of Salem?", "answer": "Days of Our Lives", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d185103b17032616b590fc", "question": "What century poem contains the earliest reference to Robin Hood?", "answer": "1370", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339222", "question": "As a child, what did Casper the Friendly Ghost die from?", "answer": "Pneumonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a952561d1b4d384d5d675", "question": "What are \"Castanets\"?", "answer": "A type of musical instrument", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133896c", "question": "Who replaced Severus Snape as Potions Master at Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75f", "question": "Pepsi Blue was a Pepsi flavored with what?", "answer": "Berries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c1ce4f032c0db195b479", "question": "What religious figure was murdered at Canterbury Cathedral on December 29, 1170?", "answer": "Thomas Beckett was Archbishop of Canterbury", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f5", "question": "What 2003 film was subtitled \"The Far Side of the World\"?", "answer": "Master and Commander", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e9", "question": "In which California city does the 1982 film \"Poltergeist\" take place?", "answer": "Cuesta Verde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c4af877e98cb977789a3", "question": "Which two African countries merged into Tanzania?", "answer": "Tanganyika and Zanzibar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b65", "question": "What Kubrick film feature gangs of punks loose in future England?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b02", "question": "The ending vocal riff of what 1966 Frank Sinatra song inspired the name of cartoon character dog Scooby-Doo?", "answer": "Strangers in the Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c64ffbde8045e48466b5", "question": "The asteroid that killed the dinosaurs is believed to have landed where?", "answer": "About 65 million years ago, an asteroid about 6 miles wide crashed into the Gulf of Mexico, killing 70% of all species on Earth.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba9", "question": "What country produced Saab automobiles?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c372", "question": "How many carats is pure gold?", "answer": "24", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4e", "question": "The 1999 Russell Crowe film \"The Insider\" concerned a whistle-blower in what industry?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2eb858d116dab4aecb41", "question": "Who played the role of Wayne Szalinski in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Rick Moranis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d209bb53d1af65886505", "question": "Who played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 film \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bccb", "question": "What werewolf-themed cereal briefly joined Count Chocula on store shelves in 1974?", "answer": "Fruit Brute", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b842", "question": "Who comes after the US vice president in the line of presidential succession?", "answer": "Speaker of the House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ea", "question": "Who is the creator of Perry Mason?", "answer": "Erle Stanley Gardner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa56e2c73aa70ea0b70b2e", "question": "In Portugal, what object is traditionally thrown at friends in celebration of April Fool's Day?", "answer": "Flour (Flour bombing' is an established April Fool's Day practice in Portugal and some other countries.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a2906c0f9723ab15cb43", "question": "Where was oldest sculpture of a human figure discovered?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e96d06d333868d34d755", "question": "Which is the world's oldest island?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b748", "question": "What country invented the Winter Olympic sport of bobsleigh?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c759", "question": "What human organs are affected by glaucoma?", "answer": "The eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11d", "question": "What Monty Python movie was banned in Norway?", "answer": "Life of Brian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c3", "question": "What kinds of creatures were Flopsy and Mopsy in the first book by Beatrix Potter?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ea", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \" Good evening, everyone, and welcome to a wonderful evening of theater and picking up after yourselves", "answer": "Principal Skinner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0b", "question": "What former US president founded the University of Virginia?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df9", "question": "Gene Hackman's \"French Connection\" cop is nicknamed for what cartoon character?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a107", "question": "\"Eyes Wide Shut\" was the last film of which director?", "answer": "Stanley Kubrick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af9858caeb0982ee455954e", "question": "Which physical force is the only one that is always attractive, never repulsive?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8c", "question": "Alfred Jingle appears in which Dickens novel?", "answer": "The Pickwick Papers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e93a613d6f11f394a3b2d54", "question": "What is the name of the Air company in the movie \"The Lorax\"?", "answer": "O'Hare Air", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a103", "question": "Directed by Sydney Pollack, which film won the Oscar for Best Picture in 1986?", "answer": "Out of Africa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba3", "question": "What woman's name is the correct term for a female donkey?", "answer": "Jenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ccf7a10b37b32637bdc44bf", "question": "What is it called when the liquid vapor pressure equals to the pressure of the gas above it?", "answer": "Boiling Point", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bf", "question": "How old was Marilyn Monroe when she died?", "answer": "36", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b908", "question": "What can you sit on that has a pommel, cantle and flap?", "answer": "A saddle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef61876ce05a3942286e53", "question": "Which Hall of Fame British rocker is also an astrophysicist?", "answer": "Brian May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592206baa4edfd43a087adef", "question": "What is the first element on the Periodic Table?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65de31f3c0ead6880d623", "question": "In 1472, Leonardo da Vinci became a member of which Florentine guild?", "answer": "Painter's Guild", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf4", "question": "Petroselinum crispum is the Latin name of which herb?", "answer": "Parsley", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a77a20565ad31a57c7e9", "question": "What Christmas tradition possibly came from the Pagan festival Saturnalia?", "answer": "Kissing under the mistletoe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdc", "question": "Who was the only president of the Confederate States of America?", "answer": "Jefferson Davis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27a", "question": "What is the syrup drained from raw sugar?", "answer": "Molasses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ee", "question": "What is a N\u00e9v\u00e9?", "answer": "Young, partially compressed snow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65f491f3c0ead6880d637", "question": "The word \"salary\" was inspired by people getting paid with what?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84b", "question": "The Ryder Cup is awarded in what sport?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20d", "question": "What US president was born in Kinderhook, New York?", "answer": "Martin Van Buren", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c585", "question": "The material nylon is named after which 2 cities?", "answer": "New York and London", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae81", "question": "Which US president lived at the Monticello mansion?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc3", "question": "Which country was the scene of the Mau Mau rebellion in the 1950s?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf38", "question": "What is the Islamic equal to the Red Cross?", "answer": "Red Crescent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe12ceae39efa6330e0fec8", "question": "Hawaii's tallest mountain is on which island?", "answer": "Hawai'i", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec260b8dc25ca9e12ef644", "question": "London's Trafalgar Square Christmas tree is traditionally given by which country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e48", "question": "What word do we derive from the Salish Indian word for \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010ca540775fa611bce67f7", "question": "What mythical beast suffers from a condition known as lycanthropy?", "answer": "Werewolves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2f", "question": "Which band member of Milli Vanilli died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Rob Pilatus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338934", "question": "Approximately how many lines is \"Beowulf\", the longest Old English manuscript?", "answer": "Over 3,000", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea48b7ff048f679a45abb2", "question": "What natural biological defense system protects the body from disease and fights off germs?", "answer": "Immunity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c300", "question": "Which elephant can't be domesticated, the African or Indian?", "answer": "The African", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95c", "question": "The Purple Heart is awarded for which reason?", "answer": "For wounds received by enemy action while on active service", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d3", "question": "Which company introduced Comet cleanser back in 1956?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae5", "question": "What Shakespeare play is often called the Scottish play?", "answer": "MacBeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbe", "question": "What fairytale girl eats the window pane of the witch's cottage?", "answer": "Gretel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a9", "question": "Who starred as John Drake in the TV show \"Secret Agent\"?", "answer": "Patrick McGoohan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25040b63e5727cf5a4836", "question": "In which country would you find the informally named \"The Enver Hoxha Mausoleum\" landmark?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b596", "question": "Which building has been nicknamed \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "GE Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab17", "question": "Where's the famed Arch of Hadrian?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6b84ffb6c85e9e634ff4e", "question": "What nationality is golfer Paul Azinger?", "answer": "American", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b66", "question": "What was the first name of Dr. Frankenstein?", "answer": "Victor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b3", "question": "Mimas orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e6", "question": "What is Entomology the study of?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133919e", "question": "Who played Renton in the 1996 movie \"Trainspotting\"?", "answer": "Ewan McGregor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd50ca00d154d7af00b8d8", "question": "Scott Raynor is the original drummer of which rock band?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b2124fda37788a9a1db7", "question": "Armagnac is a brandy originating from which area of France?", "answer": "Gascony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b296", "question": "Washington's famous crossing of the Delaware was en route to what Revolutionary War battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Trenton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3d1294f032c0db195b49b", "question": "Who did the Austrian army attack in the Battle of Kar\u00e1nsebes?", "answer": "Itself", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f4c6ff048f679a45aacb", "question": "Lockiophobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Childbirth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c27", "question": "What is the oldest symphony orchestra in the US?", "answer": "New York Philharmonic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b787364247bf200fb873", "question": "Which famous tapestry commemorates the Norman conquest of England?", "answer": "The Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba48", "question": "What US city hosts the world's largest hot air balloon festival?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b030", "question": "Before becoming Vice-\u00adPresident, Joe Biden represented what state in the US Senate?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a6", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399bb", "question": "What was the name of the Clampett\u2019s dog on \"The Beverly Hillbillies\"?", "answer": "Duke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb08b8ecf631c2414a13b62", "question": "What team won the first NBA game?", "answer": "New York Knicks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fcc1d53c97eb73f6a51a277", "question": "Which is farther north, Newfoundland or Great Britain?", "answer": "Great Britain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b84", "question": "Who was the first singer to have five #1 singles off of one album?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81d04d0de9af39e9d468a", "question": "Why was 46 B.C.E. called the \"year of confusion\"?", "answer": "It had two extra months", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ca3e3244f0f6af5b066647", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 21?", "answer": "Zepto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ab", "question": "What kind of a head does a Hieracosphinx possess?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c2", "question": "What animal lives in a \"drey\"?", "answer": "The squirrel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1df", "question": "In the restaurant world, what does \"Blue-plate special\" refer to?", "answer": "Low-priced specials that change daily", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5efa93f1ccb363a2cbc52278", "question": "What is the largest landlocked county in England?", "answer": "Shropshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b4e601dd7bf43be5e7c9", "question": "What is the only US state with an official jelly?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a909", "question": "What major river runs through Baghdad?", "answer": "Tigris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f1687cf7c52aae91cc07c8", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af0", "question": "What type of animal is Napoleon, in George Orwell\u2019s novel \u201cAnimal Farm?\u201d", "answer": "A pig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fb", "question": "What was the capital city of West Germany from 1949 to 1990?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9c", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, what is the value of the letter \"Z\"?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c242", "question": "How many daily tides are there if they are diurnal?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6b", "question": "What is Dodger Stadium also known as?", "answer": "Chavez Ravine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000eefb9a72b906b34e3cf7", "question": "Hematology is a branch of medicine involving the study of what?", "answer": "Blood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec88acec223966ae8f8821", "question": "LCS is the acronym for a professional eSports league centered around which game?", "answer": "League of Legends", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a99820565ad31a57c807", "question": "Who said, \"The buck stops here\"?", "answer": "Present Harry Truman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc6", "question": "Which album did David Bowie release in 1983?", "answer": "Let's Dance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbe3", "question": "On the game of Battleship, how many hits does it take to sink the submarine?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b624", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is represented by a bull?", "answer": "Taurus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f9", "question": "Who wrote the novels \"The Deceiver\" and \"The Fist of God\"?", "answer": "Frederick Forsyth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078bb90eee65b76b9f266c", "question": "Invented by James Caleb Jackson in 1863, which was the first cold breakfast cereal?", "answer": "Granola", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c5", "question": "Who composed the song \"Rhapsody in Blue\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d9", "question": "Which artist recorded the 1982 hit song \"Bad to the Bone\"?", "answer": "George Thorogood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6d", "question": "Which author first became famous under the pseudonym Norman Bean?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51a8aff04d658268c9306", "question": "Odysseus left home to fight in what war?", "answer": "Trojan War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f2", "question": "What note is the highest string of a violin usually tuned to?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8a", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is O'Shea Jackson?", "answer": "Ice Cube", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b206", "question": "On what saint's day in 1572 did Catherine de Medicis have 3,000 Protestants killed in Paris?", "answer": "St. Bartholomew's Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8d36ec223966ae8f8850", "question": "Which NBA personality actually owns the term \"three-peat\", referring to a team winning three consecutive championships?", "answer": "Pat Riley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600244cb4be4723ccac221a8", "question": "What painting attracted more visitors to the Louvre Museum after it was stolen?", "answer": "When the\u00a0\"Mona Lisa\"\u00a0was stolen in 1911, it caused a media sensation, and visitors queued for hours to see the vacant wall.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3235cfbf195a31e15d73b3", "question": "Which singer was known as \"The Walrus of Love\"?", "answer": "Barry White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc7", "question": "What Los Angeles neighborhood witnessed six days of rioting in 1965?", "answer": "Watts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590087785304ceedb84e8997", "question": "Until World War II, solid blocks of what was commonly used as currency in Siberia?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e5", "question": "What game was invented when Winnie-the-Pooh accidentally dropped a fir cone off a bridge?", "answer": "Poohsticks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e1", "question": "Who directed the classic horror film \"The Birds\"?", "answer": "Alfred Hitchcock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b982", "question": "What does a chrome-dome have a shortage of?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a426", "question": "In which country would you find St. Basil's cathedral?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66dd0a5bfecdd737e08a7", "question": "What is the currency of Poland?", "answer": "Zloty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82f", "question": "What traditional dish is served at Wimbledon?", "answer": "Strawberries and cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d40", "question": "What famous Dutch artist was born on July 15, 1606?", "answer": "Rembrandt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a45", "question": "According to Greek mythology, what was the only spirit that remained in Pandora's box?", "answer": "Hope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa74c73838c5c8a417f36", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c6f49076251badbead4", "question": "Who once owned the land on which Arlington National Cemetery is situated?", "answer": "Confederate General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6644ea5bfecdd737e0853", "question": "Who was the highest-paid TV host in 2018?", "answer": "Judge Judy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a135", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl's mother?", "answer": "Nana Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c642877e98cb977789b5", "question": "Bibimbap is a traditional rice dish from which region?", "answer": "Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339936", "question": "Who played Willie Scott in the movie \"Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom\"?", "answer": "Kate Capshaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c654877e98cb977789b7", "question": "The Semper Opera House is located where?", "answer": "Dresden, Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a5", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Forrest Gump\"?", "answer": "Robert Zemeckis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c06", "question": "Who wrote \"A History of the English-Speaking Peoples\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "arts"}]